Brian R. Keating

Chicago, IL • <u>brikeats.github.io</u> • <u>brikeats@gmail.com</u>

Summary

Computer vision expert with 9 years of experience in image analysis and deep learning applied to medical and satellite imagery. Expert in real-time signal processing for motion tracking with multiple publications validating new technologies. Image analyst in a data science group, comfortable communicating with non-technical colleagues.

Skills

Computer Vision & Image Analysis

Convolutional neural networks for image classification and object detection; image filtering, registration, segmentation; object tracking; camera calibration.

Programming Languages

Python and scientific Python stack (numpy, scipy, sklearn, pandas, skimage); opency; pytorch for deep learning and convolutional neural networks; working knowledge of bash/Linux; C++, Matlab for MRI work; some Java (Android) for personal projects.

Data Analysis & Machine Learning

Signal processing; Kalman filtering; modeling of biomechanical motion; independent component analysis; conjugate gradient optimization; manipulation, labeling and analysis of large image datasets; classical statistics for clinical data analysis.

Communication

Start-to-finish design, coding, execution, and publication of human studies to validate new motion-correction technologies; multiple academic conference presentations for mixed audiences of engineers and physicians; pitching computer vision solutions to prospective clients.

Education

College of William & Mary, Williamsburg, VA Ph.D. in Physics	2007
St. Mary's College of Maryland, St. Mary's City, MD B.A. in Physics	2003

Employment & Research Experience

Computer Vision Engineer

2016-present

Uptake, Inc.

- Lead a small Data Science R&D group responsible for building Uptake's capabilities in image analytics.
- Develop object detection and change detection algorithms using both classical image analysis and deep learning for use with remotely sensed imagery.
- Work with engineers to build a reusable and scalable image analysis pipeline in order to accelerate deployment of computer vision models.
- Design, implement, and train convolutional neural networks on GPUs; created and labeled a 30,000-image dataset.

Research Computing Center (RCC), University of Chicago

- Scripted image processing segmentation, registration, filtering, tracking for microscopy and MRI research.
- Provided software installation and tech support for users of a 13,000 node cluster.
- Taught "Image Analysis in Python" and "Introduction to RCC" workshops.

Assistant Researcher (Junior Faculty)

2011-2014

Dept. of Medicine, University of Hawaii

- Pioneered novel methods for correction of patient motion during MR image acquisition.
- Implemented real-time motion correction algorithms in C++ for use in clinical studies.
- Received an intramural NIH grant to adapt MRI motion correction technology for use in a neonatal population.
- Supported the lab by scripting data analysis, mentoring new hires, and organizing a journal club.

Magnetic Resonance Research Specialist

2008-2011

Dept. of Medicine, University of Hawaii

- Designed and implemented MR pulse sequences and image reconstruction programs in C++.
- Implemented a brain imaging program for a large, multi-center pediatric study.
- Provided general lab support by scripting fMRI statistical analysis in Matlab, operating the scanner, and recruiting study volunteers.

Research Assistant / Ph.D. Candidate

2004-2007

Dept. of Physics, College of William & Mary

- Programmed fluid and plasma simulations for massively parallel computers using the Lattice Boltzmann Method (LBM).
- Investigated numerical stability and implementation of boundary conditions in LBM simulations of turbulent flow.
- Coded simulations from scratch in MPI-Fortran.

Patent Pending

"Systems, devices, and methods for detecting false movements for motion correction during a medical imaging scan", <u>US patent application 15222811</u>, with Thomas Ernst, Aditya Singh, Maxim Zaitsev, and Michael Herbst.